<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-12-16T14:14:48+00:00</updated><id>https://watermeloninfo.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">WatermelonInfo</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">I-140 National Importance</title><link href="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/i140-national-importance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I-140 National Importance"/><published>2024-12-14T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-14T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/i140-national-importance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/i140-national-importance/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="national-importance-argument-for-niw-prong-1">National Importance Argument for NIW (Prong 1)</h1> <p>To write a strong argument for <strong>Prong 1</strong> of the NIW (National Interest Waiver), you must establish that the beneficiary’s work has substantial intrinsic merit and benefits the United States on a national scale.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="important-points">Important Points</h2> <ul> <li><strong>Prong 1</strong> is likely the most important part of the petition.</li> <li>Ensure the argument includes both <strong>substantial merit</strong> and <strong>national importance</strong>.</li> <li>Clearly identify the endeavor with particularity.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="structure">Structure</h2> <h3 id="1-introduction-describe-the-field-of-work">1. Introduction: Describe the Field of Work</h3> <ul> <li>Clearly state the field or area of work in which the beneficiary is involved (e.g., healthcare, engineering, environmental science, etc.).</li> <li>Provide a brief overview of why this field is of national importance.</li> </ul> <h3 id="2-describe-the-specific-contributions-of-the-beneficiary">2. Describe the Specific Contributions of the Beneficiary</h3> <ul> <li>Provide detailed examples of the beneficiary’s work and explain its impact beyond the local or regional level.</li> <li><strong>Focus Areas</strong>: <ul> <li><strong>Research and Development</strong>: Highlight important innovations or breakthroughs.</li> <li><strong>Policy Impact</strong>: Note if their work influenced national policies or strategies.</li> <li><strong>Recognition</strong>: Include awards, grants, or other honors demonstrating the significance of their work.</li> <li><strong>Economic Impact</strong>: Explain how their work has generated economic benefits like job creation or advancing U.S. competitiveness.</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <h3 id="3-provide-evidence-of-national-scope">3. Provide Evidence of National Scope</h3> <p>Demonstrate that the beneficiary’s work has implications and benefits on a national scale. Include examples such as:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Publications</strong>: Articles in peer-reviewed journals, books, or other national/global publications.</li> <li><strong>Collaborations</strong>: Partnerships with U.S.-based organizations, agencies, or corporations.</li> <li><strong>Conference Participation</strong>: Presentations at national conferences, workshops, or government panels.</li> <li><strong>Funding and Grants</strong>: Support from national funding sources for their research or projects.</li> <li><strong>Media Coverage</strong>: Examples of national media coverage highlighting their contributions.</li> </ul> <h3 id="4-link-to-national-priorities-or-us-policy">4. Link to National Priorities or U.S. Policy</h3> <ul> <li>Clearly connect the beneficiary’s work to U.S. national priorities, strategic goals, or public policy initiatives.</li> <li>Relevant areas may include public health, environmental sustainability, national defense, economic development, etc.</li> </ul> <h3 id="5-explain-the-national-importance-of-their-specific-contribution">5. Explain the “National Importance” of Their Specific Contribution</h3> <ul> <li>Directly address how the beneficiary’s work serves the U.S. on a national level.</li> <li>Demonstrate that their work contributes to addressing national challenges and priorities, beyond mere relevance.</li> </ul> <h3 id="6-summarize-the-national-importance">6. Summarize the National Importance</h3> <ul> <li>End the argument for <strong>Prong 1</strong> by reinforcing the broader national importance of the beneficiary’s work.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="reference">Reference</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.uscis.gov/policy-manual/volume-6-part-f-chapter-5">USCIS Policy Manual</a></li> </ul> <p><em>Initially drafted on 11/18/2024 based on information available at that time.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="NIW"/><category term="I140"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I-140 National Importance]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I-140 Recommendation Letter</title><link href="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/i140-recommendation-letter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I-140 Recommendation Letter"/><published>2024-12-13T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-13T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/i140-recommendation-letter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/i140-recommendation-letter/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="recommendation-letters-for-i-140-niw">Recommendation Letters for I-140 (NIW)</h1> <p>Letters of recommendations are not required by USCIS, but it is highly recommended to include 4-6 letters of recommendation for the following reasons:</p> <h2 id="why-recommendation-letters-are-important">Why Recommendation Letters Are Important</h2> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Demonstrating Expertise and Impact</strong><br/> NIW applicants must show that their work is of substantial merit and national importance. Letters from experts in your field can provide evidence of your significant contributions and how your work benefits the U.S. or addresses critical national needs. A strong letter can validate your claims and enhance the credibility of your application.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Supporting Your Claim of Uniqueness</strong><br/> The NIW is designed for individuals who possess unique expertise or abilities critical to the U.S. national interest. Letters from respected professionals in your field can highlight what sets you apart, underscoring how your work is distinct and valuable.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Demonstrating Recognition and Influence</strong><br/> Letters help show that others in your field recognize the importance of your work. They can provide context about your influence, the significance of your projects, and your leadership in addressing issues that align with U.S. national interests.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Establishing the Waiver Justification</strong><br/> A key element of a NIW application is showing that your work benefits the U.S. to such an extent that it justifies waiving the usual requirement of a job offer or labor certification. Letters of recommendation can support this argument, helping to prove that your work will have a lasting impact on U.S. progress.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Adding Credibility</strong><br/> High-quality letters from respected professionals or academics lend additional credibility to your application, especially if the letter writers are well-known in their respective fields.</p> </li> </ol> <h2 id="types-of-recommenders">Types of Recommenders</h2> <ul> <li><strong>Subjective</strong>: Someone who knows you personally, such as your PhD advisor, a professor you worked with, or executives from current or former jobs.</li> <li><strong>Objective or Independent</strong>: Someone who does not know you personally but is familiar with your work. These are more valuable than subjective recommenders.</li> </ul> <h2 id="basic-requirements-for-recommendation-letters">Basic Requirements for Recommendation Letters</h2> <ul> <li><strong>Relevance</strong>: Letters should come from people familiar with your work and its impact. Ideally, they should be written by experts with a credible reputation in the U.S.</li> <li><strong>Specificity</strong>: Provide concrete examples of your achievements and detail how your work aligns with U.S. national interests.</li> <li><strong>Authority</strong>: Letters from individuals with recognized authority in your field are particularly valuable.</li> <li><strong>Clarity</strong>: Clearly explain why your work is of national interest and how your qualifications meet the NIW criteria.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="structure-of-recommendation-letters">Structure of Recommendation Letters</h2> <h3 id="1-header-and-salutation">1. Header and Salutation</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Letterhead</strong>: The letter should be printed on the recommender’s official letterhead.</li> <li><strong>Date</strong>: Include the date the letter was written.</li> <li><strong>Salutation</strong>: <ul> <li><em>To Whom It May Concern</em></li> <li><em>Dear Sir/Madam</em></li> </ul> </li> </ul> <h3 id="2-introduction-paragraph-1">2. Introduction (Paragraph 1)</h3> <ul> <li>Introduce the recommender: Include their full name, title, organization, and credentials.</li> <li>Relationship to the applicant: State how the recommender knows the applicant, including the length of the relationship.</li> <li>Purpose of the letter: Briefly state that the purpose is to provide a strong recommendation for the applicant’s EB-2 NIW petition.</li> </ul> <h3 id="3-qualifications-and-expertise-of-the-recommender-paragraph-2">3. Qualifications and Expertise of the Recommender (Paragraph 2)</h3> <ul> <li>Explain the recommender’s qualifications: Include their professional background and authority in the field.</li> <li>Highlight their ability to assess the applicant.</li> </ul> <h3 id="4-description-of-the-applicants-achievements-and-contributions-paragraphs-3-4">4. Description of the Applicant’s Achievements and Contributions (Paragraphs 3-4)</h3> <ul> <li>Discuss the applicant’s background, career achievements, and expertise.</li> <li>Highlight key contributions that benefit the U.S.</li> <li>Emphasize the national importance of their work.</li> </ul> <h3 id="5-conclusion-and-strong-endorsement-paragraph-5">5. Conclusion and Strong Endorsement (Paragraph 5)</h3> <ul> <li>Reaffirm support: Summarize the applicant’s qualifications and impact.</li> <li>Strong endorsement: Offer a clear and enthusiastic recommendation.</li> <li>Offer further contact: Mention willingness to provide additional information if necessary.</li> </ul> <h3 id="6-closing">6. Closing</h3> <ul> <li>Polite closing: <em>Sincerely</em> or <em>Best regards</em></li> <li>Signature: Include the recommender’s signature, printed name, title, and contact information.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="references">References</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.uscis.gov/i-140">USCIS Form I-140</a></li> </ul> <p><em>Initially drafted on 11/15/2024 based on information available at that time.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="NIW"/><category term="I140"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I-140 Recommendation Letter]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I-140 Overview</title><link href="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/i140-overview/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I-140 Overview"/><published>2024-12-09T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/i140-overview</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/i140-overview/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="i-140-overview">I-140 Overview</h1> <h2 id="1-cover-letter">1. Cover Letter</h2> <p>A detailed letter addressed to USCIS summarizing the applicant’s qualifications, achievements, and reasons for the NIW request.</p> <p>The cover letter outlines how the petition satisfies the <strong>Matter of Dhanasar</strong> criteria.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-forms-and-filing-fees">2. Forms and Filing Fees</h2> <ul> <li><strong>Form I-140</strong>: The Immigrant Petition for Alien Workers.</li> <li><strong>Filing Fee</strong>: A check or money order for the required fee (currently $700 as of 2024).</li> <li><strong>Form G-28</strong> (if using an attorney): Notice of Entry of Appearance as Attorney or Accredited Representative.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="3-table-of-contents">3. Table of Contents</h2> <p>A detailed table listing all supporting documents included in the petition package, with corresponding exhibit numbers for easy reference.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="4-applicant-information">4. Applicant Information</h2> <ul> <li>Copy of passport biographical page.</li> <li>Proof of current immigration status (e.g., I-94 record, visa, or employment authorization).</li> <li>Updated résumé or CV detailing education, work experience, publications, and accomplishments.</li> <li><strong>Form ETA-9089</strong></li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="5-evidence-supporting-the-niw-criteria">5. Evidence Supporting the NIW Criteria</h2> <p>Organized into three sections following the <strong>Matter of Dhanasar</strong> framework:</p> <h3 id="a-substantial-merit-and-national-importance">a) Substantial Merit and National Importance</h3> <ul> <li>Detailed explanation of the proposed endeavor.</li> <li>Evidence of the endeavor’s relevance to national interests, such as economic, scientific, health, or educational benefits.</li> <li>Supporting documents, e.g.: <ul> <li>Published articles or reports about the importance of the field.</li> <li>Market research or industry data supporting the endeavor’s significance.</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <h3 id="b-well-positioned-to-advance-the-endeavor">b) Well-Positioned to Advance the Endeavor</h3> <ul> <li>Evidence of the applicant’s ability to make meaningful contributions, such as: <ul> <li>Academic degrees, certifications, or training.</li> <li>Published research or articles.</li> <li>Awards, honors, or recognition.</li> <li>Letters of recommendation from experts in the field, confirming the applicant’s expertise and accomplishments.</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <h3 id="c-labor-certification-waiver-in-the-national-interest">c) Labor Certification Waiver in the National Interest</h3> <ul> <li>Explanation of why the labor certification requirement should be waived (e.g., how the applicant’s work uniquely benefits the U.S. and cannot be performed by readily available U.S. workers).</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="6-letters-of-recommendation">6. Letters of Recommendation</h2> <ul> <li>Letters from independent experts (preferably unaffiliated with the applicant) attesting to the significance of the applicant’s work and its benefit to the U.S.</li> <li>Letters from employers, collaborators, or mentors highlighting the applicant’s qualifications.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="7-supporting-documentation">7. Supporting Documentation</h2> <ul> <li>Evidence of professional impact: <ul> <li>Citation records or bibliometric analysis (for researchers).</li> <li>Evidence of patents, innovations, or products developed by the applicant.</li> <li>Proof of collaboration or contributions to high-profile projects.</li> <li>Media coverage, awards, or invitations to conferences.</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="8-exhibit-list">8. Exhibit List</h2> <p>A detailed, numbered list of all exhibits included in the petition.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="9-binder-or-folder-organization">9. Binder or Folder Organization</h2> <p>The petition is typically submitted in a well-organized binder or folder with tabs dividing sections for easy navigation.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="optional">Optional:</h3> <p>If premium processing is available (currently limited for EB-2 NIW):</p> <ul> <li>Include <strong>Form I-907</strong> and the additional processing fee.</li> </ul> <hr/> <p>The quality and clarity of your submission significantly impact the outcome. If you’d like, I can assist in drafting a cover letter, organizing evidence, or preparing your documentation.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="references">References</h3> <ul> <li>USCIS Form I-140: <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/i-140">https://www.uscis.gov/i-140</a></li> </ul> <hr/> <p><em>Initially Drafted on 11/13/2024 based on information available at that time.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="NIW"/><category term="I140"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I-140 Overview]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Qualify for NIW</title><link href="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/qualify-niw-well-positioned/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Qualify for NIW"/><published>2024-12-04T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-04T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/qualify-niw-well-positioned</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/qualify-niw-well-positioned/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/overview-niw.png" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/overview-niw.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <h1 id="well-positioned">Well Positioned</h1> <h2 id="second-prong-the-person-is-well-positioned-to-advance-the-proposed-endeavor">Second Prong: The Person is Well Positioned to Advance the Proposed Endeavor</h2> <p>Unlike the first prong, which focuses on the merit and importance of the proposed endeavor, the second prong centers on the person. The person needs to be “well positioned to advance the endeavor.”</p> <hr/> <h3 id="factors-not-an-exclusive-list">Factors: (not an exclusive list)</h3> <ul> <li>The person’s education, skills, knowledge, and record of success in related or similar efforts;</li> <li>A model or plan that the person developed, or played a significant role in developing, for future activities related to the proposed endeavor;</li> <li>Any progress towards achieving the proposed endeavor; and</li> <li>The interest or support garnered by the person from potential customers, users, investors, or other relevant entities or persons.</li> </ul> <p>The petitioner should submit evidence to document the person’s past achievements and corroborate projections related to the proposed endeavor.</p> <p>Claims cannot be unsubstantiated or implausible, but does not need to demonstrate that the proposed endeavor is more likely than not to ultimately succeed.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="examples-of-evidence-not-exclusive-list">Examples of evidence: (not exclusive list)</h3> <ul> <li>Degrees, certificates, or licenses in the field;</li> <li>Patents, trademarks, or copyrights developed by the person;</li> <li>Letters from experts in the person’s field, describing the person’s past achievements and providing specific examples of how the person is well positioned to advance the person’s endeavor;</li> <li>Published articles or media reports about the person’s achievements or current work;</li> <li>Documentation demonstrating a strong citation history of the person’s work or excerpts of published articles showing positive discourse around, or adoption of, the person’s work;</li> <li>Evidence that the person’s work has influenced the field of endeavor;</li> <li>A plan describing how the person intends to continue the proposed work in the United States;</li> <li>A detailed business plan or other description, along with any relevant supporting evidence, when appropriate;</li> <li>Correspondence from prospective or potential employers, clients, or customers;</li> <li>Documentation reflecting feasible plans for financial support (see below for a more detailed discussion of evidence related to financing for entrepreneurs);</li> <li>Evidence that the person has received investment from U.S. investors, such as venture capital firms, angel investors, or start-up accelerators, and that the amounts are appropriate to the relevant endeavor;</li> <li>Copies of contracts, agreements, or licenses showing the potential impact of the proposed endeavor;</li> <li>Letters from government agencies or quasi-governmental entities in the United States demonstrating that the person is well positioned to advance the proposed endeavor;</li> <li>Evidence that the person has received awards or grants or other indications of relevant non-monetary support (for example, using facilities free of charge) from federal, state, or local government entities with expertise in economic development, research and development, or job creation; and</li> <li>Evidence demonstrating how the person’s work is being used by others, such as, but not limited to: <ul> <li>Contracts with companies using products that the person developed or assisted in developing;</li> <li>Documents showing technology that the person invented, or contributed to inventing, and how others use that technology;</li> <li>Patents or licenses for innovations the person developed with documentation showing why the patent or license is significant to the field.</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="references">References:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.uscis.gov/policy-manual/volume-6-part-f-chapter-5">USICS policy manual</a></li> </ul> <hr/> <p>Initially Drafted on 11/12/2024 based on information available at that time.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="NIW"/><category term="qualification"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well Positioned]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Qualify for NIW</title><link href="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/qualify-niw-national-importance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Qualify for NIW"/><published>2024-11-26T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-26T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/qualify-niw-national-importance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/qualify-niw-national-importance/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/overview-niw.png" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/overview-niw.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <h1 id="national-importance">National Importance</h1> <h2 id="first-prong-the-proposed-endeavor-has-both-substantial-merit-and-national-importance">First Prong: The Proposed Endeavor has both Substantial Merit and National Importance</h2> <h3 id="endeavor">Endeavor</h3> <p>The term “endeavor” is more specific than the general occupation; a petitioner should offer details not only as to what the occupation normally involves, but what types of work the person proposes to undertake specifically within that occupation.</p> <p>For example, while engineering is an occupation, the explanation of the proposed endeavor should describe the specific projects and goals, or the areas of engineering in which the person will work, rather than simply listing the duties and responsibilities of an engineer.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="substantial-merit">Substantial Merit</h3> <p>The endeavor’s merit may be demonstrated in areas including, but not limited to, business, entrepreneurship, science, technology, culture, health, or education.</p> <p>USCIS values evidence of the endeavor’s potential significant economic impact, but:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Merit may be established without immediate or quantifiable economic impact.</strong></li> <li><strong>Endeavors related to research, pure science, and the furtherance of human knowledge may qualify, whether or not the potential accomplishments in those fields are likely to translate into economic benefits for the United States.</strong></li> </ul> <p>Endeavors such as classroom teaching, for example, without broader implications for a field or region, generally do not rise to the level of having national importance for the purpose of establishing eligibility for a national interest waiver.</p> <p><strong>Note:</strong> This is a highly subjective standard. The petitioner should focus on discussing the endeavor and its national importance.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="national-importance-1">National Importance</h3> <p>Officers must also examine the national importance of the specific endeavor proposed by considering its potential prospective impact.</p> <p>Officers should focus on the nature of the proposed endeavor, rather than only the geographic breadth of the endeavor. For example, the endeavor:</p> <ul> <li><strong>May have national importance because it has national or even global implications within a particular field, such as certain improved manufacturing processes or medical advances.</strong></li> <li>Economically, it may have <strong>“significant potential to employ U.S. workers”</strong> or <strong>“other substantial positive economic effects, particularly in an economically depressed area.”</strong></li> </ul> <p>Petitioners should submit a detailed description explaining the proposed endeavor and supporting documentary evidence to establish that the endeavor is of national importance.</p> <p>Ultimately, if the evidence demonstrates that the person’s proposed endeavor has the <strong>significant potential to broadly enhance societal welfare or cultural or artistic enrichment</strong>, or to <strong>contribute to the advancement of a valuable technology or field of study</strong>, it may rise to the level of national importance.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="references">References</h2> <ul> <li>USCIS Policy Manual: <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/policy-manual/volume-6-part-f-chapter-5">Volume 6, Part F, Chapter 5</a></li> </ul> <p><em>Initially drafted on 11/11/2024 based on information available at that time. Revised on 11/12/2024.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="NIW"/><category term="qualification"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[National Importance]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Qualify for NIW</title><link href="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/qualify-niw-exceptional-ability/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Qualify for NIW"/><published>2024-11-25T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-25T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/qualify-niw-exceptional-ability</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/qualify-niw-exceptional-ability/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/overview-niw.png" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/overview-niw.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <h1 id="exceptional-ability">Exceptional Ability</h1> <h2 id="two-step-test">Two-Step Test</h2> <h3 id="step-1-evidence-types">Step 1: Evidence Types</h3> <p>The petitioner must meet at least 3 out of the 6 evidence types:</p> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Academic Record</strong><br/> An official academic record showing that the beneficiary has a degree, diploma, certificate, or similar award from a college, university, school, or other institution of learning relating to the area of exceptional ability.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Experience</strong><br/> Evidence in the form of letter(s) from current or former employer(s) showing that the beneficiary has at least 10 years of full-time experience in the occupation in which they are being sought.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Licenses or Certifications</strong><br/> A license to practice the profession or certification for a particular profession or occupation.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Salary or Remuneration</strong><br/> Evidence that the beneficiary has commanded a salary or other remuneration for services that demonstrates exceptional ability.<br/> <em>Note:</em> The evidence must show that the salary or remuneration is indicative of exceptional ability relative to others in the field.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Membership in Professional Associations</strong><br/> Evidence of membership in professional associations.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Recognition for Achievements</strong><br/> Evidence of recognition for achievements and significant contributions to the industry or field by peers, governmental entities, or professional or business organizations.</p> </li> </ol> <p><em>Note:</em> Affidavits can be provided to demonstrate qualifications. In some cases, evidence relevant to one criterion may be applicable to other criteria.</p> <h3 id="step-2-final-merits-determination">Step 2: Final Merits Determination</h3> <p>Meeting the minimum requirement of providing at least three types of initial evidence does not, in itself, establish that the beneficiary qualifies for exceptional ability classification. The officer must review the evidence as a whole to determine whether the petitioner meets the burden of proof.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="references">References</h2> <p>USCIS Policy Manual: <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/policy-manual/volume-6-part-f-chapter-5">Volume 6, Part F, Chapter 5</a></p> <hr/> <p><em>Initially drafted on 11/8/2024 based on information available at that time.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="NIW"/><category term="qualification"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exceptional Ability]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Qualify for NIW</title><link href="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/qualify-niw/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Qualify for NIW"/><published>2024-11-24T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-24T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/qualify-niw</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/qualify-niw/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/overview-niw.png" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/overview-niw.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <h1 id="advanced-degree">Advanced Degree</h1> <h2 id="master-or-phd">Master or PhD</h2> <p>Prepare the following:</p> <ul> <li>A copy of the diploma.</li> <li>A copy of transcripts from the highest degree earned.</li> </ul> <p><strong>Note:</strong> Keep the documents concise to avoid confusing the officer. If the degree was earned outside of the US, a credential evaluation report is required. If a doctoral degree is customarily required, you must have a United States doctorate or its foreign equivalent degree.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="bachelor-with-five-years-of-experience">Bachelor with Five Years of Experience</h2> <p>Prepare the following:</p> <ul> <li>A copy of the diploma.</li> <li>A copy of transcripts from the bachelor’s degree.</li> <li>Employment verification letters indicating work experience.<br/> <a href="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/assets/pdf/Employment_Verifiacation_Letter_Template.pdf">link to the employment verification letter template</a></li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="credential-evaluation-for-foreign-degrees">Credential Evaluation for Foreign Degrees</h2> <p>If the degree was earned from universities outside of the US, provide a credential evaluation report for the highest degree relevant to the application.</p> <p><strong>Key Points:</strong></p> <ul> <li>USCIS does not endorse any specific agency.</li> <li>A course-by-course evaluation is not required; a general evaluation suffices, showing the equivalency of the foreign degree to a US degree.</li> </ul> <h3 id="recommended-evaluation-agencies">Recommended Evaluation Agencies</h3> <ol> <li><strong>WES (World Education Services):</strong> <ul> <li>One of the most recognized credential evaluation services in the U.S.</li> <li>Trusted by universities, employers, and licensing boards.</li> <li>Known for precise evaluations of international degrees.</li> </ul> <p><strong>For Chinese applicants:</strong><br/> WES only accepts certifications authenticated by 学信网 (CHSI). Complete the CHSI certification first and then submit it to WES. This usually takes 1-2 weeks, although processing times during holidays may be longer.</p> </li> <li><strong>FIS (Foreign Credential Services of America):</strong> <ul> <li>Offers a more affordable and simpler process.</li> <li>Provides translation services.</li> </ul> </li> </ol> <hr/> <h2 id="references">References</h2> <ul> <li>USCIS Policy Manual: <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/policy-manual/volume-6-part-f-chapter-5">Volume 6, Part F, Chapter 5</a></li> </ul> <hr/> <p><strong>Document History:</strong></p> <ul> <li>Initially drafted on 11/6/2024 based on information available at the time.</li> <li>Revised on 11/7/2024.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="NIW"/><category term="qualification"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced Degree]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Basics of NIW</title><link href="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/basics-of-niw/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basics of NIW"/><published>2024-11-13T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-13T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/basics-of-niw</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://watermeloninfo.github.io/blog/2024/basics-of-niw/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="basics-of-niw">Basics of NIW</h1> <p>The National Interest Waiver (NIW) is a U.S. immigration option that allows foreign nationals to apply for a green card based on employment without the need for a specific job offer or the lengthy labor certification process. NIW applicants typically must show that their work is in the “national interest” of the United States, benefiting the country significantly in areas like healthcare, technology, research, or other important sectors.</p> <h3 id="applicants-generally-need-to-demonstrate">Applicants generally need to demonstrate:</h3> <ol> <li><strong>Advanced Degree</strong></li> <li><strong>Substantial merit and national importance</strong></li> <li><strong>Well-positioned to advance the proposed endeavor</strong></li> <li><strong>National Interest</strong>: It would be beneficial to the United States to waive the job offer and labor certification requirements</li> </ol> <h3 id="timeline">Timeline</h3> <p>Preparation → I-140 → I-485 or consular processing, depending on whether you are in the US. Priority date (PD) is the date shown on the I-140 receipt. You can file a change of status as long as the I-140 is approved and the PD is current.</p> <h3 id="important-websites-for-diy-niw">Important websites for DIY NIW:</h3> <ul> <li> <p><strong>USCIS policy manual</strong>: <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/policy-manual/volume-6-part-f-chapter-5">https://www.uscis.gov/policy-manual/volume-6-part-f-chapter-5</a>. The manual guides how officers review each case.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>I-140 website</strong>: <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/i-140">https://www.uscis.gov/i-140</a>. USCIS provides instructions on how to fill out forms like I-140 and I-485.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Visa Bulletin</strong>: <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/legal/visa-law0/visa-bulletin.html">https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/legal/visa-law0/visa-bulletin.html</a>. Shows waiting times, updated monthly.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Important Dates</strong>: The received date is the same as the priority date. Table A is crucial, as it indicates when you can complete the process, often corresponding with an interview date. Table B shows dates when you can file for a change of status.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Evaluate waiting time</strong>: <a href="https://www.mygcvisa.com/calculator/">https://www.mygcvisa.com/calculator/</a>.</p> </li> </ul> <hr/> <h1 id="国家利益豁免-niw">国家利益豁免 (NIW)</h1> <p>国家利益豁免（NIW）是美国的一种移民途径，允许外国公民在无需特定工作邀请或漫长的劳工认证流程的情况下，基于工作申请绿卡。NIW 申请人通常必须证明其工作符合美国的“国家利益”，在医疗、科技、研究或其他重要领域对美国有显著的益处。</p> <h3 id="申请人通常需要证明">申请人通常需要证明：</h3> <ol> <li><strong>拥有高级学位</strong></li> <li><strong>具有重要价值和国家重要性</strong></li> <li><strong>在推动所提出的事业方面具有良好的优势</strong></li> <li><strong>国家利益</strong>：豁免工作邀请和劳工认证的要求将有利于美国</li> </ol> <h3 id="流程">流程</h3> <p>准备 → I-140 → I-485 或领事处理（取决于是否在美国）。优先日期（PD）显示在 I-140 收据上，只要 I-140 获批且排期到了，就可以提交身份转换申请。</p> <h3 id="diy-niw-的重要网站">DIY NIW 的重要网站：</h3> <ul> <li> <p><strong>USCIS 政策手册</strong>: <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/policy-manual/volume-6-part-f-chapter-5">https://www.uscis.gov/policy-manual/volume-6-part-f-chapter-5</a>. 该手册指导移民官如何审查每个案例。</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>I-140 网站</strong>: <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/i-140">https://www.uscis.gov/i-140</a>. USCIS 提供有关如何填写 I-140 和 I-485 等表格的说明。</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>签证公告</strong>: <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/legal/visa-law0/visa-bulletin.html">https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/legal/visa-law0/visa-bulletin.html</a>. 显示等待时间，每月更新。（重要日期: 收件日期与优先日期相同。表 A 很重要，标志着可以完成流程的日期，通常会通知面试。表 B 列出可以提交身份转换申请的日期。）</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>评估等待时间的长短</strong>: <a href="https://www.mygcvisa.com/calculator/">https://www.mygcvisa.com/calculator/</a>.</p> </li> </ul> <hr/> <p><em>Initially Drafted on 11/5/2024</em> <em>Drafted mainly based on USCIS website and Chapter 2 of “Oscar Green card”.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="NIW"/><category term="basics"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Basics you should know about NIW]]></summary></entry></feed>